# Brittany Pecenka

Web Developer with experience in Ruby on Rails development, as well as Front End user interface design, testing, debugging, and code generation. Proven and advanced communication skills for developing relationships with subject matter and clients.

#### WEB DEVELOPER

4014 W. Hollow Creek Drive Peoria, IL • 61615 brittany.pecenka@gmail.com brittanypecenka.com linkedin.com/blpecenka

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Web Developer Mcomm Group, Inc. | Peoria, IL | 2016-Present

- Development and maintenance of Ruby on Rails code base, including legacy code and new projects
- MySQL database architect and data visualization
- Front End design, development and implementation throughout sites available at brittanypecenka.com
- Project Management over the following projects: myplumbingtraining.com and bestestimatepro.com

**English Teacher** 

Carrot English | Seoul, Korea | Remote-Online | 2015-2016

• Construct insightful English lessons through phone and video platforms for students from Korea and China.

Sales Specialist + Supervisor Running Central | Peoria, IL | 2012-2015

- Directly lead the sales team through daily activities on the sales floor, including employee guidance, individual and team training, as well as managing customer care solutions.
- Successfully led the sales team on multiple occasions in highest total revenue, units per transaction, and individual sales.

## **EDUCATION**

International Teaching Certifications American TESOL Institute | Tampa, FL | 2012

- Business English
- English for Children

Bachelors Degree Illinois State University | Bloomington, IL | 2012

• Linguistics + Communications

## LANGUAGES

English | Native

French

Italian

Spanish

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Ruby on Rails
HTML5 + CSS3 + Sass
JavaScript + jQuery
Bootstrap

## DATABASE

MySQL MySQL Workbench

GitHub + Bitbucket

#### TOOLS

File Transfer Protocol
WordPress
Linux + Windows
Microsoft Office
Integrated Development Environments

## SAMPLE WORK

myplumbingtraining.com

mcommgroup.com/NHAg miningallin.com test.bestestimatepro.com aheadofthegrade.com

## RESOURCES

LinkedIn GitHub CodePen